Robert Moses Papers
Robert Moses Papers
1937-1972
Moses, Robert, 1888-1981.
14.0 linear ft.
The papers of the American city planner and administrator of the Triborough Bridge Authority and the Power Authority of the State of New York include bound and unbound reports containing articles, speeches, and clippings by and about Moses. Much of the material concerns transportation improvements and hydroelectric plants at Niagara Falls and Messena.
149347
Biographical History
As New York's controversial "master builder," Robert Moses played major role in molding the state's physical environment. He occupied a variety of state and city posts, including president of Long Island State Park Commission and chairman of State Council of Parks (1924-63), New York City parks commissioner (1943-60), chairman of New York State Power Authority (1954-63), and chairman of Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority (1954-63). Between 1924 and 1968, Moses developed public works costing $27 billion, including eleven bridges, 481 miles of highway, 658 playgrounds, seventy-five state parks, and such projects as Jones Beach, Shea Stadium, the United Nations, and Lincoln Center. He died in West Islip, New York in 1981. [from Current Biography Copyright (c) by The H. W. Wilson Company]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Moses Papers comprise one series: General files. These files are largely bound volumes, Reports, and brochures, magazine articles, speeches, and news clippings written by or about Robert Moses. They are arranged by year. Later articles and miscellaneous, 1967-1972, are not bound.
Many of these records deal with transportation improvements as well as other accomplishments in New York City. Robert Moses was also instrumental in the hydroelectric power programs in New York State and there are papers concerning power plants at Niagara Falls and Messena.
Also included throughout the collection are copies of Moses' Newsday newspaper column and several articles of correspondence with George Zabriskie.
Notice: The material in this collection may be protected by copyright law (Title 17, U. S. Code).
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Politics, government and public administration; New York State; Moses, Robert, 1888-1891.; Power Authority of the State of New York.; Triborough Bridge Authority.; City planners -- United States.; City planning -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hydroelectric power plants -- New York (State) -- Messena.; Hydroelectric power plants -- New York (State) -- Niagara Falls.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Reports.; Speeches (documents); City planners.; Transportation.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- General files
  - Bound reports
    - Reports, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1939-1941 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1940-1942 (Box 1)
    - Reports, 1942-1943 (Package 1)
    - Reports, 1946 (Package 1)
    - Reports, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Reports, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Reports (volume I), 1949 (Box 2)
    - Reports (volume II), 1949 (Package 1)
    - Reports, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Reports (volume I), 1951 (Box 2)
    - Reports (volume II), 1951 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1954; 2 volumes (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1956; 3 volumes (Box 5)
    - Reports, 1957; 3 volumes (Box 6)
    - Reports, 1958; 2 volumes (Box 6)
    - Reports, 1958; 1 volume (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1959; 3 volumes (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1960; 4 volumes (Box 8)
    - Reports, 1961; 1 volume (Box 8)
    - Reports, 1961; 3 volumes (Box 9)
    - Reports, 1962; 3 volumes (Box 9)
    - Reports, 1962; 5 volumes (Box 10)
    - Reports, 1963; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Reports, 1963; 3 volumes (Box 11)
    - Reports, 1964; 3 volumes (Box 11)
    - Reports, 1964; 1 volume (Box 12)
    - Reports, 1965; 3 volumes (Box 12)
  - Unbound reports
    - Articles and speeches, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Newsday column and miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Tribourough, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Newsday column, articles and miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Speeches, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Tribourough brochures, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Articles etc., 1968-1972; 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Zabriskie correspondence (Box 14)